好的，上次我开始说话的时候
alright last time I started talking
关于线性化能力，我想
about linearize ability and I want to
结束这一次，我们之所以要
finish up this time the reason why we're
再说一遍就是这是我们的
talking about it again is that it's our
一种关于什么的标准定义
kind of standard definition for what
强一致性意味着在存储方面
strong consistency means in storage
设置系统样式，例如，实验3是
style systems so for example lab 3 is a
需要服从你的实验室3需要
needs to obey your lab 3 needs to be
可线性化，有时这将
linearizable and sometimes this will
上来吧，因为我们在谈论一个
come up because we're talking about a
高度一致的系统，我们正在
strongly consistent system and we're
想知道一种特定的行为
wondering whether a particular behavior
是可以接受的，其他时候是线性化的
is acceptable and other times linearize
能力会变得越来越强，因为
ability will become come up because
我们将谈论的是一种
we'll be talking about a system that
是不可线性化的，我们将会
isn't linearizable and we'll be
想知道你知道它会以什么方式
wondering you know in what ways might it
达不到线性化或偏离线性化
fall short or deviate from linearize
能力所以你需要做的一件事就是
ability so one thing you need to be able
要做的就是观察特定的序列
to do is look at a particular sequence
操作的特定执行
of operations a particular execution of
一些执行读取和
some system that executes reads and
像你的实验3一样写作，并且能够
writes like your lab 3 and be able to
回答我的问题哦，就是这样吗？
answer the question oh was that was that
史蒂文斯的行动我刚刚看到了
Stevens of operations I just saw
不管是不是可以线性化，我都要去，所以我们要走了
linearizable or not I'm so we're going
继续练习这一点
to continue practicing that a little bit
现在再加上我会试着确定
now plus I'll try to actually establish
一些有趣的事实将会是
some interesting facts that will be
对我们了解它的意义很有帮助
helpful for us about what it means about
对我们的系统造成的后果
the consequences for the systems we
构建和查看线性化能力是
build and look at linearize ability is
要查找有关特定操作历史记录的信息，请执行以下操作
to find on particular operation history
所以我们一直在谈论的事情
so always the thing we're talking about
哦，我们观察到你知道一系列
is oh we observed you know a sequence of
客户的请求，然后他们得到了
requests by clients and then they got
在不同时间的一些反应和
some responses at different times and
他们要的是不同的你
they asked for different different you
知道读取不同的数据并获得
know to read different data and got
不同的答案，你知道的是
various answers back you know is that
我们看到的历史是可以线性化的，所以
history that we saw linearizable ok so
这里有一个历史的例子，
here's an example of a history that
可能被线性化，也可能不被线性化
might or might not be linearized able so
让我们假设在某个时间点
let's suppose at some point in time some
客户群的时间将转移到
client groups of times gonna move to the
右边这条竖线表示时间
right this vertical bar marks the time
在那里一个客户发送了一个请求，我是
at which a client sent a request I'm
我要用这个符号来表示
gonna use this notation to mean that the
请求为写入，并请求设置
request is a write and asks to set
变量或键或任何x2值%0
variable or key or whatever x2 value 0
所以这可以说是一个键和一个值
so sort of a key and a value this would
对应于关键字X的PUT且为零
correspond to a put of key X and by zero
在实验室3，然后这是某种意义上的我们
in lab 3 and then this is sort of we're
监视客户端向客户端发送的内容
watching what the client send the client
将此请求发送到我们的服务，并在
sent this request to our service and at
在某一点上，该服务做出了响应，
some point the service responded and
说，是的，你是对的，所以完成了
said yes you're right is completed so
我们承担的是一种性质的服务
we're assuming the services of a nature
它实际上会告诉您何时写入
that actually tells you when the write
完成，否则定义不是
completes otherwise the definition isn't
非常有用，好的，所以我们有这个要求
very useful ok so we have this request
有人来写，然后我就
by somebody to write and then I'm
想象一下在这个例子中有
imagining in this example there's
另一个要求是因为我要
another request that because I'm putting
这里的这个标记表示第二个
this mark here this means the second
在第一个请求之后启动的请求
request started after the first request
做完了，你知道为什么
finished and and you know reason why
这一点很重要，因为这条规则
that's important is because of this rule
可线性化的历史必须与
that linearizable history must match
实时，而这真正的意思是
real time and what that really means is
这些请求实际上是已知的
that requests that are known in real
是时候在另一些事情之后开始了
time to have started after some other
请求已完成第二个请求具有
request finished the second request has
中的第一个请求之后发生
to occur after the first request in
不管我们订出什么顺序，那都是
whatever order we work out that's the
证明历史是线性化的
proof that the history was a linearized
将可用的OK线性化，这样就可以了
linearize available ok so in this
举个例子，我在想，还有另一个
example I'm imagining there's another
要求写X的请求有
request that asks to write X to have
值1，然后是并发请求
value 1 and then a concurrent request
可能会晚一点开始，因为
may be started a little bit later as to
把X设为2我说现在我们有两个可能
set X to 2 I said now we have two maybe
两个不同的客户端在以下位置发出请求
two different clients issued requests at
将X设置为2的时间大致相同
about the same time to set X to two
不同的价值观，所以我们当然
different values so of course we're
想知道哪一个会是
wondering which one is going to be the
真正的价值，然后我们也有一些
real value and then we also have some
如果你所有的东西都写得很好，那就去读吧
reads if all you have is writes well
好吧，你说对了，所以这很难
well you have us right so it's it's hard
对可线性化说得太多了
to say too much about linearizable
线性化能力，因为你不知道
linearize ability because you don't know
你没有任何证据证明这个系统
you don't have any proof that the system
实际上做了什么或者透露了什么
actually did anything or revealed any
值，所以我们真的需要阅读，所以让我们
values so we really need reads so let's
想象一下我们有一些读物，除非你
imagine we have some read unless you'll
在历史上看到我们的
be seeing our in the history
一位客户说要在这个时候阅读
that a client said to read at this time
第二次它得到的答案是
and the second time it got an answer for
红键重音对SO有价值
red key accent got value to so
大概真的看到了这个价值，
presumably actually saw this value and
然后又有了另一个请求，可能是
then there was another request by maybe
相同的客户端或不同的客户端
the same client or a different client
但已知是在之后的时间里开始的
but known to have started in time after
此请求已完成，X的此读取
this request finished and this read of X
获得了价值，所以问题是
got value while and so the question in
摆在我们面前的是这段历史
front of us is is this history
可线性化，有两种
linearizable and there's sort of two
我们可以采取的策略我们也可以
strategies we can take we can either
编造一个序列是因为如果我们能
cook up a sequence because if we can
想出这五个人的总共顺序
come up with a total order of these five
符合实时和实时要求的操作
operations that obeys real time and in
每次读取都会看到写入的值
which each read sees the value written
由牧师主持，最近一次进行
by the priest most recently proceeding
如果我们能赶上来的话就按顺序进行
right in the order if we can come up
有了这个订单，那就证明了
with that order then that's a proof the
历史是可以线性化的另一种策略
history is linearizable another strategy
就是观察这些规则每一条
is to observe that these rules each one
可能暗示这件事发生在那之前
may imply certain this comes before that
图中的边，如果我们能找到一个
edges in a graph and if we can find a
此操作中的循环必须早于
cycle in this operation must come before
我们可以在那次行动中找到一个心理医生
that operation we can find a psych on
这张图证明了
that graph and that's proof that the
历史是不能线性化的
history isn't linearizable and for small
历史上我们也许真的能够
histories we may actually be able to
列举每一单订单和使用
enumerate every single order and use
这表明这段历史并不是
that show this history isn't
不管怎样都可以线性化任何想法
linearizable anyway any any any thoughts
关于这是否可能是或可能不是
about whether this might be or might not
是可线性化的
be linearizable
是
yes
是的，好的，那么观察结果是，嗯
yes okay so the observation is that um
我们看到有一点麻烦
it's a little bit troubling that we saw
使用Iu读取-然后使用读取
read with IU - and then the read with
想要价值，也许这是矛盾的
value want and maybe that contradicts
你知道有两种权利，一种是
you know there were two rights one with
一对一的价值-所以我们
value one on one value - so that so we
当然，如果我们必须带着价值去阅读
certainly if we had to read with value
三个，这显然会是一件很重要的事情
three that would obviously be something
我大错特错了，你知道的，但是我们
I got terribly wrong you know but we got
两人中有一人的权利和一人的权利
there were a right of one in two and a
读一读和二读，所以问题是
read of one and two so the question is
此读取顺序是否可以
whether this order of reads could
可能会和解的方式
possibly be reconciled with the way
这两项权利在历史上都有体现。
these two rights show up in the history
好的，所以我是什么，我是什么，我们是什么游戏
okay so what I'm what I'm the game we're
打球就是我们有大概两个
playing is that we have a like maybe two
客户或三个客户，他们是
clients or three clients and they're
谈论一些你知道的服务，也许是
talking some service you know maybe a
去年木筏上的一些东西和我们是什么
raft last year something and what we are
查看请求和响应是正确的
seeing is requests and responses right
所以这意味着我们看到
so what this means is that we saw
来自客户端的将X写入
requests from a client to write X to the
你知道，把X和1的请求放在一起
you know put requests for X and one and
我们看到了这里的回应，所以我们所知道的
we saw the response here so what we know
是不是在这段时间的某个地方
is that somewhere during this interval
时间的长短，大概这项服务实际上
of time presumably the service actually
在内部更改x-1的值并
internally change the value of x - 1 and
这意味着在某个地方
what this means is that somewhere in
在此时间间隔内，服务
this interval of time the service
可能改变了它内部的想法
presumably changed its internal idea of
x-2的值在这里的某个位置
the value of x - 2 somewhere in this
时间，但你知道，它只是在某个地方
time but you know it's just somewhere in
这一次并不意味着它发生了
this time it doesn't mean it happened
在这里还是在这里回答你的问题
here or here does that answer your
问题
question
是
yes
是的，好的，那么观察是这样的
yes okay so the observation is that is
是可以线性化的，而且它一直伴随着
linearizable and it's been accompanied
通过线性化的实际证明
by an actual proof of the linearize
能力，也就是一种能力的展示
ability namely a demonstration of the
表明它是可线性化的阶数
order that shows that it is linearizable
顺序是，是的，它是可线性化的
and the order is yes it's linearizable
并且顺序是X的第一个右边，带有
and the order is first right of X with
值0，并且服务器同时获得这两个
value 0 and the server got both of these
权利大致在同一时间
rights at roughly the same time it's
仍然不得不选择所有的顺序本身
still had to choose the order itself all
好的，这么说吧，它可能
right so let's just say it could have
先执行x2值%2的右侧
executed the right of x2 value 2 first
然后读取X，然后执行
and then the read of X then executed the
读到X，第一次读到的会是哪一个
read of X which would the first read of
X，在这一点上将产生2和
X which at that point would yield 2 and
然后我们会说下一次行动
then we're gonna say the next operation
已执行，则是X对1的权利
had executed it was the right of X to 1
中的最后一个操作
and then the last operation in the
历史是从X到1的读数，因此
history is the read of X to 1 and so
这证明了历史是
this is proof that the history is
可以线性化，因为这里有一个顺序
linearizable because here's an order
这是整个行动的顺序
it's a total order of the operations and
这是它实时匹配的顺序
this is the order it matches real time
所以这意味着我们走吧
so what that means is well just go
通过它，X到0的权利就来了
through it the the right of X to 0 comes
首先，这完全是
first and that's that's totally
很直观，因为它实际上已经完成了
intuitive since it's actually finished
在任何其他操作开始之前，
before any other operations started the
X对1的权利来了抱歉
right of X to 1 comes sorry the rate of
X到2排在第二位，所以我们要说
X to 2 comes second so we're gonna say
也许我会在这里做这样的标记
maybe that I'm gonna mark here that sort
我们想象这些的实时时间
of real time at which we imagine these
行动恰好证明了
operations happen to demonstrate that
这里的订单是实时匹配的，所以
the order here does match real time so
它会说我会在这里写一个大X
it'll say I'll just write a big X here
来纪念我们想象这一切的时间
to mark the time when we imagine this
手术发生得很好，所以那是
operation happened all right so that's
第二次手术之后我们就
the second operation then we're
假设下一个操作是
imagining that the next operation is the
读过X of 2 We，你知道没有
read of X of 2 we you know there's no
因为读取X而导致的实时性问题
real time problem because the read of X
2的实际上是这个u同时发生的吗？
of 2 actually was this u concurrently
有了2的X的右边，你就知道它是
with the right of X of 2 you know it's
不像X的权利，也不像X的读法
not like the right of X the read of X of
2做完了，然后才做了正确的事
2 finished and only then did the right
X的权利，X的权利，从那里开始
of X right of X with to start there
真的是同时发生的，我们可以想象一下
really are concurrent we'll just imagine
那就是说
that that
在这个时间点上
sort of point in time at which this
发生的手术就在那里，所以
operation happened is right there so
这就是你知道我们不在乎什么时候
this is the you know we don't care when
这件事发生了，这么说吧
this one happened let's just say there's
第一次行动，第二次，第三次现在我们
the first operation second third now we
我只想说，我有X的权利
have a right of X of one let's just say
它在这里实时发生，只是必须
it happens here in real time just has to
在发生的操作之后发生
happen after the operations that occur
在它之前的顺序，所以这将是说
before it in the order so that will say
有第四次手术，现在我们
there's the fourth operation and now we
有x1的读数，它可以很漂亮
have the read of x1 and it can pretty
任何时候都会发生很多事情，但让我们直说吧
much happen at any time but let's say it
在这里发生，好的，所以这是
happens here okay so this is the
钻石
Diamonds
所以我们有一个订单，这是
so we have the order this is the
证明该命令是
demonstration that the order is
与实时一致，那就是我们可以
consistent with real time that is we can
为每个操作选择一个时间
pick a time for each of the operations
这是在它的开始和结束时间内
that's within its start and end time
这将导致这一总订单
that would cause this total order to
与我们的实时顺序相匹配，因此
match our real time order and so the
最后一个问题是，每个人都看过
final question is did each read see the
价值由最密切的
value written by the most closely
同一变量的前一权利，因此
preceding right of the same variable so
这个读数前面有两个V
there's two V's this read preceded by a
正确的值，所以这是
right with that correct value so that's
很好，这个阅读之前有一个
good and this read is preceded by a
最接近的右边前面有一个右边
right most closely preceded by a right
同样的值也可以，所以这个就是这个
of the same value also okay so this this
证明了这段历史是
is a demonstration that this history was
可线性化，你知道的，你知道的
linearizable and you know the you know
这要看你当时是怎么想的
depends on what you thought when you
第一次看到历史，但它不是
first saw the history but it's not
始终立即清除该设置
always immediately clear that set up
这很复杂，你知道这很容易
this complicated is you know it's easy
当你看着这些的时候，你会上当受骗
to be tricked when looking at these
你认为哪段历史哦
histories which do you think oh the
先从x1的右边开始，所以我们只是
right of x1 started first so we just
在某种程度上假设第一个值
sort of assumed that the first value
写的肯定是一个，但那实际上是
written must be one but that's actually
这里不是必需的，关于以下方面的任何问题
not required here any questions about
这
this
如果你是说如果这两个人
if the you mean if these two were moved
像这样没问题，所以如果这样的话
like this the okay so if if if this if
仅颁发了具有价值的权利
the right with value to was only issued
由客户在读完口音后
by the client after the read of accent
返回的值不会是
value to returned that wouldn't be
可线性化，因为无论按什么顺序
linearizable because in whatever order
你知道我们拿出的任何订单都有
you know any order we come up with has
遵守实时命令，所以任何
to obey the real-time ordering so any
我们想出的命令将不得不
order we come up with would have had to
把读X放在…之前
have the read of X with to precede the
X的右边有2，因为没有
right of X with 2 and since there's no
这里的X/2洞察力的其他权利
other right of X of 2 insight here that
意味着此时的读取可能
means that a read at this point could
只能看到0或1，因为它们是
only see 0 or 1 because those are the
只有其他两项权利可能
only other 2 rights that could possibly
在这之前读一读是如此感人，你知道吗？
come before this read so moving you know
把这些移开那么多就会
shifting these that much makes the would
使示例不可线性化
make the example not linearizable
是
yes
我是说第一条垂直线
I'm saying that the first vertical line
是客户端将
is the moment the client sends the
请求，第二条垂直线是
request and the second vertical line is
当客户端收到
the moment the client receives the
请求，是的，是的，所以这是一个非常
request yes yeah yeah so this is a very
以客户为中心的定义
client centric kind of definition it
他说你知道客户应该看看
says you know clients should see the
遵循行为和发生的事情
following behavior and what happens
在我们发出请求之后，也许会有
after us send a request in maybe there's
很多复制品可能会很复杂
a lot of replicas maybe a complicated
网络谁知道它几乎什么都没有
network who knows what it's almost none
在我们的业务中，我们只是
of our business we're only the
定义仅涉及哪些客户端
definition is only about what clients
看，这里有一些灰色区域，我们将
see there's some gray areas which we'll
很快就会苏醒过来，就像客户
come to in a moment like if the client
那么应该需要重新传输请求
should need to retransmit a request then
我们还得让你知道这是
we also have to you know that's
一些我们必须考虑的事情，好的，所以
something we have to think about okay so
这个是可线性化的，这里是另一个
this one is linearizable here's another
例如，我实际上要从
example I'm actually going to start out
因为它几乎一模一样，所以我要
with it being almost identical I'm gonna
开始的时候，你和我是一模一样的
start out with you being identical for
第一个示例，同样，我们有一个
the first example so again we have a
X的右边有0，我们有这两个
right of X with 0 we have these two
同时拥有的权利和我们拥有的相同权利
concurrent rights and we have the same
到目前为止完全相同的两个读数
two reads those are so far identical to
上一个示例因此我们
the previous example so therefore we
知道这一定是这件事一定是这件事
know this must be this alone must be
最小化，但我要添加，让我们
minimal but I'm going to add let's let's
假设客户端1发出了这两个命令
imagine that client 1 issued these two
请求的定义实际上并不是
requests the definition doesn't really
关心客户，而不是她自己的理智
care about clients but her own sanity
将假设客户端1为红色X，并看到两个
will assume client 1 red X and saw two
后来又红了X，看到了一个，但是
and then later red X and saw one but
到目前为止没问题，我说还有另一个
that's okay so far I say there's another
客户端和另一个客户端执行读取
client and the other client does a read
它会看到一个1，然后是另一个
of X and it sees a 1 and then the other
客户端是X的第二次读取，它看到
client is a second read of X and it sees
-所以这是可线性化的，我们要么
- so this is linearizable and we either
必须拿出一份订单
have to come up with an order
或者这出现在具有以下特征的图表之前
or this comes before that graph that has
其中的一个循环
a cycle in it
所以你知道这件事
so you know that thing this is getting
问题是如果一个客户看到
at the puzzle is if one client saw
这里只有两个权利所以他们会让你
there's only two rights here so they you
以任何顺序或其中一项权利知道
know in any order or one of the rights
要么先来，要么另一种速度
comes first or the other rate comes
第一个也是第一个直观的客户端1
first and intuitively client one
观察到具有值为
observed that the right with value to
先来后来的是价值权
came first and then the right of value
一对这两个读数意味着
one right these two reads mean that has
情况是这样的，在任何法律命令中
to be the case that in any legal order
两个人的权利必须出现在
of the right of two has to come before
一个人的右边，以便攀登
the right of one in order for the climb
什么时候看过这个，它是一样的
when to have seen this and it's the same
我们在这里看到的顺序是对称的
order we saw over here but symmetrically
客户一的经历清楚地表明
client one's experience clearly shows
对面的右边对不起，嗯，好的
the opposite right sorry huh fine to
客户的经历正好相反
client who's experience was the opposite
客户先看到一个人的权利
clients to saw the right of one first
然后是有价值的右派
and then the right with value too and
这里的规则之一是
one of the rules here is that there's
只有一个操作的总顺序不是
just one total order of operations not
允许不同的客户端查看
allowed to have different clients see
不同的历史或不同的
different histories or different
不同的进化论和进化论
different progressions evolutions of the
存储在系统中的值
values that are stored in the system
总共只能有一个订单
there can only be one total of order
所有客户都必须体验的
that all clients have to experience
操作，这些操作与
operations that are consistent with the
一份订单，如果是这一个客户
one order and if one this one client
很明显地暗示这个顺序是正确的
clearly implies that the order is right
-然后是右边的，所以我们应该
- and then right one and so we should
不能有任何其他客户
not be able to have any other client who
观察到该订单是
observes proof that the order was
还有什么是我们这里有的吗？
anything else which is what we have here
所以这有点直观
and so that's a bit of a intuitive
对这里出了什么问题的解释
explanation for what's going wrong here
顺便说一句，之所以会这样
and and by the way the reason why this
可能会出现在我们的系统中
could come up in the systems that we
就是我们正在建造的
build and look at is that we're building
复制的系统您可能知道RAFT
replicated systems either you know raft
复制副本或可能具有缓存的系统
replicas or maybe systems with caching
但我们正在建立的系统
in them but we're building systems that
有许多数据副本，因此
have many copies of the data and so
可能有许多服务器具有以下副本
there may be many servers with copies of
它们中的X可能具有不同的值
X in them possibly with different values
在不同的时间，如果他们没有
at different times right if they haven't
还没拿到承诺还是什么的
gotten the commits yet or something some
复制副本可能有一个值，某些值可能是
replicas may have one value some may of
另一个
the other
但尽管如此，如果我们的系统
but in spite of that if our system is
可线性化或强一致性
linearizable or strongly consistent it
必须表现得好像只有一个
must behave as if there was only one
数据副本和一个线性序列
copy of the data and one linear sequence
应用于数据的操作的
of operations applied to the data that's
为什么这是一个有趣的例子
why this is an interesting example
因为这可能会在某种程度上出现
because this could come up in a sort of
有两个副本的Buggy系统
buggy system that had two copies of the
数据和一份拷贝执行这些权利
data and one copy executed these rights
一种顺序，另一种复制品
in one order and the other replicas
执行了其他订单中的权利
executed the rights in the other order
然后我们可以看到这个并将其线性化
and then we could see this and linearize
能力说不，我们看不到我们是
ability says no we can't see that we're
不允许在正确的
not allowed to see that in the correct
系统，因此图形中的循环位于
system so the the cycle in the graph in
这张图出现在那张图之前
the this comes before that graph that
将会是一种稍微多一点的证据
would be a sort of slightly more proof e
这不可线性化的证据是
proof that this is not linearizable is
两个人的权利必须先于
that the right of two has to come before
客户一读到两个，所以有一个
client ones read of two so there's one
像这样的箭头，所以这个右边必须
arrow like this so this right has to
出现在读取客户端读取之前
come before that read client ones read
必须排在X的右边，带
has to come before the right of X with
值1，否则此读取不会
value one otherwise this read wouldn't
如果可以的话，你可以看对一个吗？
be able to see one right if this you can
想象一下这种权利可能会发生在
imagine this right might happen very
在订单的前面，但是在这种情况下，这是
early in the order but in that case this
读到X就看不到它会看到的
read of X wouldn't see one it would see
两个因为我们知道这家伙看到了两个所以
two since we know this guy saw two so
X与2的读数必须在
the read of X with two must come before
X的权利，其中一个是X的权利
the right of X with one the right of X
必须在任何读取X之前出现
of one must come before any read of X
值为1，因为包括客户端
with value 1 because including client
谁读过值为1的X，但在
who's read of X with value 1 but in
在这里和这里获得值1的顺序
order to get value 1 here and for this
读一读，看看X的右边，我也是
read to see to the right of X with I too
必须在顺序中介于
must come between in in the order
在这两个行动之间所以我们知道
between these two operations so we know
X1的读数必须在
that the read of X 1 must come before
在X2的右边，这是一个循环
the right of X 2 and that's a cycle
好的，所以没有，没有维尼
alright so there's no there's no Vinnie
或者顺序之类的，但是没有线性的
or order or that but there's no linear
所有这些时间都能服从的命令
order that can obey all of these time
和价值规则，而不是因为
and value rules and there isn't because
这里面有一个循环
there's a cycle in the
在图表中是的
in the graph yes
这是个很好的问题，这个这个
that's a good question this this
定义关于的定义
definitions the definition about
历史不一定是关于制度的
history's not about necessarily systems
所以它没有说的是一个系统
so what it's not saying is that a system
设计是可以线性化的，如果某些东西
design is linearizable if something
关于设计，它真的只是
about the design it's really only
历史就是历史，所以如果我们不能
history by history so if we don't get to
了解系统如何在内部运行
know how the system operates internally
我们唯一知道的就是我们可以
and the only thing we know is we get to
在它执行的时候看着它，然后在
watch it while it executes then before
我们看到了任何我们不知道的东西
we've seen anything we just don't know
好的，我们的意思是，我们会假设它是
right we mean we'll assume it's
可线性化，然后我们可以看到更多
linearizable and then we see more and
更多操作顺序此阿卡什
more sequences of operations this Akash
它们都与线性化一致
they're all consistent with linearize
能力他们都遵循这些规则所以
ability they all follow these rules so
你知道我们认为很可能是这个
you know we believe it's probably this
不是所有的线性化，如果我们曾经
isn't linearize of all and if we ever
看到一个不是，然后我们意识到它是
seen one that isn't then we realize it's
不可线性化，所以这是，是的，这是
not linearizable so this is yeah it's
不是关于系统设计的定义
not a definition on the system design
这是一种定义，关于我们在做什么
it's a definition on what the what we
观察系统以在此基础上执行此操作
observe the system to do so in that
感觉上可能有一点
sense it's maybe a little bit
如果你试图设计一个不令人满意的
unsatisfying if you're trying to design
有些东西是对的，没有食谱
something right there's not a recipe for
你知道你是如何设计的，除了在
how you design you know except in a
微不足道的感觉是如果你有一个
trivial sense that if you had a single
非常简单的系统中的服务器一台服务器
server in very simple systems one server
数据的一份拷贝未穿线或
one copy of the data not threaded or
多核之类的，有点
multi-core or anything it's a little bit
很难建立一个违反
hard to build a system that violates
这是一个非常简单的设置，但是非常棒
this in a very simple set up but super
很容易在任何形式上违反它
easy to violate it in any kind of
分布式系统好的，所以这一课
distributed system okay so the lesson
从这一点来看，只有
from this is that there's only can only
是系统所处的一个顺序
be one order in which the system is
观察以执行全部写入
observed to execute the writes all
客户必须看到价值是一致的
clients have to see value is consistent
在系统执行写入的情况下
with the system executing the writes in
同样的订单
the same order
这是一段非常简单的历史
here's a very simple history
另一个例子是假设我们写“使徒行传”
another example supposing we write acts
值为1，然后确定
with value 1 and then definitely
随后，在时间上，可能会与另一个
subsequently in time maybe with another
客户端另一个客户端启动权限
client another client launches a right
值为2的X的值，并看到响应
of X with value 2 and sees a response
从仪式回来说，是的，我做了
back from the service saying yes I did
右边，然后第三个客户端执行
the right and then a third client does a
读了X，我就给你买了一本，所以这就是
read of X and gets got you one so this
是一个非常简单的例子，显然不是
is a very easy example it's clearly not
可线性化，因为时间规则意味着
linearizable because the time rule means
唯一可能的顺序是
that the only possible order is the
X的右边有1，X的右边是2
right of X with 1 the right of X is 2
X的读数是1，所以它必须是
the read of X with 1 so that has to be
该订单和该订单清楚地
the order and that order clearly
违反了这是唯一一个
violates this is the only one order that
秩序显然违反了第二条规则
order clearly violates the second rule
关于价值观，那就是你知道的最多
about values that is you know the most
最近右侧写入的值
value written by the most recent right
在拥有的一个订单中，这是可能的
in the owned one order that's possible
不是1，是2，所以这显然不是
is not 1 it's 2 so this is clearly not
可线性化和我带来的原因
linearizable and the reason I'm bringing
这是因为这是争论的焦点
it up is because this is the argument
一个可线性化系统强
that a linearizable system a strongly
一致的系统不能过时
consistent system cannot serve up stale
数据是正确的，您知道原因是什么
data right and you know the reason why
这可能会再次出现，你知道的
this might come up is again you know
也许你们每个人都有很多复制品
maybe you have lots of replicas each you
我知道可能还没有看到所有的权利
know maybe haven't seen all the rights
或者所有承诺的权利或者别的什么
or all the committed rights or something
所以可能会有一些，也许是所有的
so maybe there's some maybe all the
复制品已经正确地看到了这一点，但只有
replicas have seen this right but only
一些复制品已经正确地认识到了这一点
some replicas have seen this right and
所以如果你问一个落后的复制品
so if you ask a replica that's lagging
稍稍落后一点，它仍然会
behind a little bit it's still gonna
X的值为1，但是
have value 1 for X but nevertheless
客户端应该永远不会看到这一点
clients should never be able to see this
可线性化系统中的旧值是
old value in a linearizable system are
不允许陈旧的数据，不允许仍然
there no stale data allowed no still
读取数
reads
好的，如果时间间隔有重叠的话
yeah if there's overlap in the interval
然后你知道你知道你
then there's then you know that you
该系统是否可以合法地执行
could the system could legally execute
他们中的任何一个都是实时的，而我在
either of them in a real-time and I in
间隔，所以这就是意义所在
the interval so that's the sense in
他们可以系统地执行
which they could system gonna execute
现在你知道其他的顺序了
them in either order now you know other
你知道如果不是这两个人
you know if it weren't for these two
读取系统会让你知道
reads the system would have you know
写入的完全自由执行
total freedom execute that writes in
两个订单都不是因为我们看到了两个
either order but because we saw the two
读到我们知道你知道唯一
reads we know that you know the only
法律秩序是2，然后是1，是的，所以
legal order is two and then one yeah so
如果两个预备队笑了，那么
if the two reserva laughing then and
则读取可能具有的任何顺序
then any order then the reads could have
其实你知道托比看到的
seen either in fact you know Toby saw
这两个词和一个词都出自
the two and the one words all from the
读了这些小玩意儿可能会让你知道
reads these doobies could have you know
系统，直到它提交给
the system until it committed to the
读它的价值观仍然是自由的
values for the read it still had freedom
以任一顺序退还它们
to return them in either order
我把它们当做同义词，对，对，你
I'm using them as synonyms yeah yeah you
大多数人都知道，尽管有可能
know for most people although possibly
不是今天的纸张线性化能力是
not today's paper linearize ability is
定义得很好，而且是人们的
is well defined and and people's
定义确实有很大的偏差
definitions really deviate very much
从这种强烈的一致性来看，
from this strong consistency though is
更少的我认为有更少的种类
less I think there's less sort of
关于到底是什么达成了共识
consensus about exactly what the
定义可能是如果你的意思是坚强
definition might be if you meant strong
坚持不懈，通常是男人，通常是
consistency it's often men it's usually
男人的方式也很接近
men too in ways that are quite close to
这
this
比如，哦，这个系统
like for example that oh the system
的行为方式与具有以下特性的系统的行为方式相同
behaves the same way that a system with
只有一份数据拷贝会有行为
only one copy of the data would behave
好的，哪个比较接近什么？
all right which is quite close to what
我们正在研究这个定义
we're getting at with this definition
但是，是的，你知道，这是合理的
but yeah for you know it's reasonable to
假设强强一致性是
assume that strong strong consistency is
与可序列化相同，好的，这是
the same as serializable okay so this is
不可线性化，而且你知道
not linearizable and the you know the
我们得到的教训是杂草是不允许
the lesson is weeds are not allowed to
仅返回陈旧数据仅返回最新数据
return stale data only only fresh data
或者您只能返回
or you can only return the results of
最近完成的右侧
the most recently completed right
好的，我还有最后一个小例子
okay I have a final final little example
所以我们有两个客户，其中一个
so we have two clients one of them
向X提交值为3的写入
submits a write to X with value three
然后编写两个值为4的动作和
and then write two acts with value 4 and
我们还有另一个客户，你知道的
we have another client and you know at
客户端在此时间点发出
this point in time the client issues a
读到X，但这是一个你要问的问题
read of X but and this is a question you
问客户没有得到
asked the the client doesn't get a
答对了，你知道有谁知道
response right you know who knows like
它在某种实际实施中
it in the sort of actual implementation
可能是领队在某个时候坠毁了
may be the leader crashed at some point
也许他的委托人会送来阅读器
maybe the his client to sent in the read
所以领导可能没有得到
request so the leader maybe didn't get
它是因为请求已被丢弃或
it because the request was dropped or
也许领头人接到请求后
maybe the leader got the request and
执行了它，但是网络上的响应
executed it but the response the network
丢弃了回复，或者可能是领头人
dropped the response or maybe the leader
我拿到了，开始往上走
got it and started to process up and
然后在完成处理之前崩溃
then crash before finished processing
或者可能确实处理过然后崩溃了
and or maybe did process it and crash
在说出回应之前，谁知道呢？
before saying the response who knows
当客户的观点像发送
when the clients point of view like sent
一个请求，但从未得到过响应，所以在
a request and never got a response so in
客户的内部机械用于
the interior machinery of the client for
我们谈论的大多数系统
most of the systems we're talking about
客户端将重新发送
the client is going to resend the
请求可能会做不同的领导
request maybe do a different leader
也许就是那个知道怎么回事的领导人
maybe the same leader who knows what so
它把第一个问题送到了这里
it sent the first question quest here
也许它会将第二个请求发送到
and maybe it sends the second request at
你知道，这个时间点已经超时了
this point in time it times out you know
没有响应在以下位置发送第二个请求
no response sends the second request at
这一点，然后最终得到一个
this point and then finally gets a
回答说，事实证明，你是这样做的
response it turns out that and you're
我们将在实验3中实施此功能，
going to implement this in lab 3 that a
服务器处理问题的合理方式
reasonable way of servers dealing with
重复请求是针对其服务器的
repeated requests is for their servers
要使表按某种方式编制索引，请执行以下操作
to keep tables sort of indexed by some
唯一请求编号的类型或
kind of unique request number or
一些来自客户的东西，在这些东西中
something from the clients in which the
服务员记得吗，哦，我已经看过了
servers remember oh I already saw that
请求并执行它，这是
request and executed it and this was the
我发回的回复是因为你
response that I sent back because you
我不想执行两次请求
don't want to execute a request twice
你知道，如果它是一个例子，如果它是一个
you know if it's a for example if it's a
您不想执行的写入请求
write request you don't want to execute
请求正确，因此服务器必须
requests right so the server's have to
能够用过滤发出重复的请求
be able to filter out duplicate requests
而且他们必须能够退还
and they have to be able to return the
答复以重复答复，即
reply to repeat the reply that the
原来是这样的
originally
发送给该请求者，该请求者可能已经
sent to that request which perhaps has
被网络丢弃，因此服务器
dropped by the network so that servers
记住最初的窥探并重复一遍
remember the original pry and repeat it
作为对重新发送的响应，如果您这样做了
in response to the resend and if you do
你们在实验3中要做的，如果你们
that which you will in lab 3 then if you
我知道因为服务器能让领队
know since the server the leader could
在它执行
have seen value 3 when it executed the
客户端向其发出的原始读取请求
original read request from client to it
可以将值3返回值3给重复的
could return value 3 to the repeated
此时发送的请求，并且
requests that was sent at this time and
在这个时候完工，所以我们必须
completed at this time and so we have to
就这是否合法打个电话
make a call on whether that is legal
是的，你可以争辩说，哦，天哪，你
right you could argue that oh gosh you
知道我们在这里发送请求的客户吗
know the client we sent the request here
这是在X24的右边
this was after the right of X 2 4
完成了，所以上帝，你真正想要的是什么
completed so Jesus what you really
应该在这一点上返回，而不是
should return for at this point instead
3的大小，这有点像是
of 3 and this is like a little bit a
关于它的问题好像有点上升了
question of it's like a little bit up
设计者，但如果您查看的是
the designer but if what you view is
是这样的，重播是
going on is that the retransmissions are
一种低层次的担忧，这是你知道的一部分
a low-level concern that's you know part
RPC机器或隐藏在某些
of the RPC machinery or hidden in some
图书馆之类的，而且是从
library or something and that from the
客户端应用程序视点全部
client applications point of view all
发生的情况是它发送了一个
that happened was that it's sent a
请求，并得到响应
request at this time and got a response
就在这个时候，仅此而已
at this time and that's all that
从客户的角度来看
happened from the clients point of view
那么值3在这里是完全合法的
then a value of 3 is totally legal here
因为这个请求花了很长时间
because this request took a long time
它完全与
it's completely concurrent with the
对不是实时订购的
right not ordered in real time with the
对，因此要么是三个人，要么是
right and therefore either the three or
这四个是有效的，你知道的，就好像
the four is valid you know as if the
在此真正执行的读取请求
read requests that really executed here
实时地或在这里实时地
in real time or or here in real time so
更重要的教训是，如果您有客户
the larger lesson is if you have client
从应用程序重新传输
retransmissions the from the application
如果你定义的是
point of view if you're defining
来自应用的线性化能力
linearize ability from the applications
观点-即使在
point of view - even with
重传数据的实时程度
retransmissions the real time extent of
像这样的请求来自于
the requests like this is from the very
将请求第一次传输到
first transmission of the requests to
应用程序的最后时间
the final time at which the application
实际上收到了回复，可能是在
actually got the response maybe after
有很多理由是的
many reasons yes
你可能宁愿你得到新的数据而不是
you might rather you got fresh data than
陈旧的数据，你知道，如果我是你知道的
stale data you know if I'm you know
假设请求是什么时间
supposing the request is what time it
几点了，那是时间服务器I
what time is it that's a time server I
发送了一个请求，说“哦，现在几点了？”
sent a request saying Oh what time is it
它给了我一个回应，你知道的，是的。
and it sends me a response you know yeah
如果我现在发出请求但我得不到
if I send a request now and I don't get
从现在起到2分钟前的回复
the response until 2 minutes from now
伙计，有些网络问题，可能是
dude some Network issue it may be that
应用程序更愿意看到
the application would like prefer to see
我们会得到它应该得到的回应
we're gonna get the response it would
我更愿意看到一个接近的时间
prefer to see a time that was close to
在这个时间里，实际上已经得到了
the time at which had actually got the
响应，而不是深入到
response rather than a time deep in the
在它最初发送请求的时间之后
past when it originally sent the request
事实是，如果你知道如果你知道
now the fact is that if you you know if
您使用的是您拥有的这样一个系统
you're using a system like this you have
要编写容错的应用程序，请执行以下操作
to write applications that are tolerant
对于您正在使用的这些规则，
of these rules you're using a
像这样的线性化系统是
linearizable system like these are the
规则，所以你必须写下你知道的
rules and so you must write you know
正确的应用程序必须容忍
correct applications must be tolerant of
你知道，如果他们发出请求，他们
you know if they send a request and they
过一会儿就会得到回复，他们只是
get a response a while later they just
你知道你不能不被允许
you know you can't are not allowed to
编写应用程序就好像哦，天哪，如果我
write the application as if oh gosh if I
获取一个响应，该响应表示该值
get a response that means that the value
在我拿到的时候，他们的反应是一样的
at the time I got the response was equal
设置为3，这对于应用程序来说是不正常的
to 3 that is not OK for applications to
你以为你知道我有什么吗？
think you know what that I have that
针对给定应用程序播放
plays out for a given application
取决于应用程序正在执行的操作
depends on what the application is doing
我之所以提起这件事是因为
the reason I bring this up is because
这是一个常见的问题，在6、6、8到4岁的你
it's a common question in 6 6 8 to 4 you
伙计们将通过以下方式实施机器
guys will implement the machinery by
哪些服务器检测到重复项并
which servers detect duplicates and
重新发送上一个答案，即
resend the previous answer that the
最初发送的服务器和问题
server originally sent and the question
会上来的，如果你原来是这样的可以吗？
will come up is it ok if you originally
我在这里看到了在此返回的请求
saw the request here to return at this
您响应的时间点
point in time the response that you
会送回这里，如果网络
would have sent back here if the network
没有掉在地上，这是很方便的
hadn't dropped it and it's it's handy to
有一种推理的方式，我是说
have a kind of way of reasoning I mean
有这样的定义的一个原因是
one reason to have definitions like
将能力线性化，以便能够进行推理
linearize abilities to be able to reason
关于这样的问题，我是对的
about questions like that right i'm
使用这个方案，我们可以说很好
using using this scheme we can say well
按照那些规则实际上是可以的。
it actually is okay by those rules
好了，我想说的就是这些。
all right that's all i want to say about
线性化任何逗留的能力
linearize ability of any any lingering
问题是的
questions yeah
嗯，你知道，也许我太放肆了
well you know maybe I'm taking liberties
在这里，但真正发生的是
here but what's going on is that in real
我们读过的时间-和读过的
time we have a read of - and a read of
一声和一声的朗读真的来了
one and the read of one really came
在实时读取两个和之后
after in real time the read of two and
所以一定是按照这个顺序来的
so must come must be in this order in
最后的订单，也就是说必须
the final order that means there must
一直是一种权利-在这里的某个地方
have been a right of - somewhere in here
这是我们的权利，在某个地方有价值一
it's our right with value one somewhere
在这里，那是在读完-in之后
in here that is after the read of - in
在宣读完后的最后一份订单
the final order right after the read of
-在阅读其中一个之前
- and before the read of one in that
订单中必须有有价值的权利
order there must be a right with value
一只有价值的权利只有一个
one there's only one right with a value
没有空房，你知道如果还有更多的话
unavailable you know if there were more
我们也许可以玩游戏，但是
than one we maybe could play games but
只有一个空位，所以这是对的。
there's only one available so this right
必须以最后的顺序溜进这里，否则
must slip in here in the final order or
所以我觉得我可以画出这个箭头
therefore I felt able to draw this arrow
这些箭头正好捕捉到了
and these arrows just capture the sort
规则的一个接一个的含义
of one by one implication of the rules
看订单一定是什么样子的，是的。
on what the order must look like yeah
好的，是的，我的意思是任何时候或者X，那么
all right yeah I mean any hour or X so
哪位抱歉哪位是他自己的RX1
which sorry which which yeah his own rx1
他在他自己的RX1之前就看到了，好的，那么
he sees it before his own rx1 okay so
途经，是的，我们不是，我们不是
the via yep well we're not we're not
我们真的不能说是哪一个
we're not really able to say which of
这两颗小麦先到，所以我们不能
these two wheats came first so we can't
如果我们是认真的，这一切都是错误的
quite for all this error if we mean this
用于约束最终顺序的箭头
arrow to constrain the ultimate order
我们不是你知道的这两种杂草
we're not you know the these two weeds
可能有两种顺序，所以我们不会
could come in either order so we're not
允许我说这件事发生在那之前
allowed to say this one came before that
一种可能是有一个更简单的循环
one it could be there's a simpler cycle
实际上，然后我画了画，所以我是认真的
actually then I've drawn so I mean it
可能是因为可以肯定的是
may be because certainly the that the
损坏在这四项中，我同意。
damage is in these four items I agree
有了这两个，这四个项目
with that these two these four items
在某种程度上是主要的证据
kind of are the main evidence that
有些事不对劲
something is wrong
现在是一个循环我不确定是不是
now whether a cycle I'm not sure whether
有一个循环就是涉及到这一点
there's a cycle that just involves that
可能会好的，这是值得的
there could be okay this is worth
想着因为你知道如果我不能
thinking about cuz you know if I can't
想点更好的，否则我就
think of anything better or I'll
我当然会问你一个关于
certainly ask you a question about
期中考试的可线性化历史
linearizable histories on midterm
好的，那么今天的报纸今天的报纸
okay so today's paper today's paper
动物园管理员和我的意思是部分原因
zookeeper and I mean part of the reason
我们甚至是动物园管理员的纸就是它
we're even zookeeper paper is that it's
一个成功的现实世界系统，它是一个
a successful real world system it's an
开放源码您知道的服务
open source you know service that
实际上，罗恩去过的人很多
actually a lot of people ron has been
融入了很多现实世界
incorporated into a lot of real world
软件，所以有一种特定的
software so there's a certain kind of
现实和成功，但是你知道
reality and success to it but you know
从这一点来看，这让人觉得很有吸引力
that makes attractive from the point of
在某种程度上支持这样一种观点的观点
view of kind of supporting the idea that
动物园管理员的设计可能实际上是
the zookeepers design might actually be
一个合理的设计，但我们之所以
a reasonable design but the reason we're
对它感兴趣我对它感兴趣
interested in in it I'm interested in it
更准确地说，是为了
is for to somewhat more precise
技术上的观点那么我们为什么要
technical points so why are we looking
在这篇论文中，其中之一就是在
at this paper so one of them is that in
与你的救生筏形成鲜明对比的是
contrast to raft like the raft you've
就像定义的那样，它是书面的和木筏的
written and raft as that's defined it's
真的是一个您知道的库，您可以使用
really a library you know you can use a
筏子库作为一些更大的
raft library as a part of some larger
复制系统，但RAFT不像
replicated system but raft isn't like a
独立服务或您
standalone service or something that you
你可以和它说话，这是你真的必须要说的
can talk to it's you really have to
将您的应用程序设计为在
design your application to interact at
明确地描述了筏子库，这样您就可以
the raft library explicitly so you might
不知道这是个有趣的问题
wonder it's an interesting question
是否有一些有用的系统
whether some useful system sort of
独立的通用系统可以
standalone general-purpose system could
被定义为对以下方面有帮助的
be defined that would be helpful for
人们构建独立的分布式建筑
people building separate distributed
像“有没有”这样的系统提供一些服务？
systems like is there serve some service
可以咬掉很大一部分
that can bite off a significant portion
为什么构建分布式是痛苦的
of why it's painful to build distributed
系统，并将其打包在一个
systems and sort of package it up in a
您认识的任何人都可以提供独立服务
standalone service that you know anybody
所以这才是真正的问题所在
can use so this is really the question
的API会是什么样子的
of what would an API look like for a
一般用途，我就叫它，我不是
general purpose I'll call it I'm not
当然可以，像这样的东西的正确名称是什么？
sure what the right name for things like
动物园管理员是，但你有一个将军
zookeeper is but you've got a general
目的协调服务
purpose coordination service
另一个问题，另一个问题
and the other question the other
动物园管理员有趣的一面是
interesting aspect of zookeeper is that
当我们构建复制系统并
when we build replicated systems and
动物园饲养员复制系统是因为
zookeepers a replicated system because
在其他事情中，它就像一个
among other things it's it's like a
容错
fault-tolerant
通用协调服务和
general-purpose coordination service and
它和大多数产品一样具有容错能力
it gets fault tolerance like most
按复制划分的系统，即存在
systems by replication that is there's a
你们中的一些人可能知道三五个人
bunch of you know maybe three or five or
七个或者谁知道是什么
seven or who knows what
动物园管理员服务器需要花钱才能买到
zookeeper servers it takes money to buy
这些服务器就像一台7号服务器
those servers right like a 7 server
设置动物园管理员的费用是
zookeeper setup is 7 times expensive as
一种简单的单一服务器，所以它
a sort of simple single server so it's
我很想问你是不是买了7
very tempting to ask if you buy 7
运行复制服务的服务器
servers to run your replicated service
你能把表演提高7倍吗？
can you get 7 times the performance out
7台服务器中的任何一台都是正确的，并且您知道如何
of your 7 servers right and you know how
我们能不能这样做，这样
could we possibly do that so the
问题是你知道我们有n倍于
question is you know we have n times as
许多服务器可以为我们带来n倍的收益
many servers can that yield us n times
所以我要说的是
the performance so I'm gonna talk about
第二个问题首先是从
the second question first so from the
关于这个讨论的观点
point of view this discussion about
我正要去看演出
performance I'm just going to view
动物园饲养员只是一项我们不提供的服务
zookeeper as just some service we don't
我真的很在乎这项服务是什么，但是
really care what the service is but
使用类似筏子的复制进行复制
replicated with a raft like replication
系统动物园管理员实际上运行在
system zookeeper actually runs on top of
这个叫Zab的东西是为我们的
this thing called Zab which for our
目的
purposes
我们就当几乎是
we'll just treat as being almost
和木筏一模一样，我只是
identical to the raft and I'm just
我担心的是
worried about the performance of the
我并不真的担心复制
replication I'm not really worried about
动物园管理员具体在做什么呢？
what zookeepers specifically is up to so
大体情况是你知道我们
the general picture is that you know we
有一堆客户，可能有几百个
have a bunch of clients maybe hundreds
可能有数百个客户，我们有
maybe hundreds of clients and we have
就像小伙子们一样，我们有一个领袖
just as in the lads we have a leader the
Leader有一个动物园管理员层，
leader has a zookeeper layer that
客户与之交谈，然后在
clients talk to and then under the
ZooKeeper层是XAB系统，它
zookeeper layer is the xab system that
然后，就像木筏一样管理复制
manages replication then just like rafts
这是一大堆正在做的事情
what was a a lot of what's that is doing
正在维护包含
is maintaining a log that contains the
客户端拥有的操作顺序
sequence of operations that clients have
送来的真的很像木筏
sent in really very similar to raft may
有一堆这样的东西，每个都有
have a bunch of these and each of them
有日志，但这是一个挂起的新请求
has a log but it's a pending new request
这是一个熟悉的设置，所以
that's a familiar set up so the
克林顿在请求和扎布层
Clinton's in a request and the Zab layer
您知道，将该请求的副本发送到
you know sends a copy of that request to
每个复制品和复制品
each of the replicas and the replicas
把这个附加到他们的内存法则中，我会
append this to their in-memory law I'd
可能保存在磁盘上，所以他们
probably persisted onto a disk so they
如果他们坠毁了，可以把它拿回来
can get it back if they crash and
重新启动，因此问题是在我们添加
restart so the question is as we add
更多的服务器，你知道，我们可以有四台
more servers you know we could have four
服务器或五七台或其他任何服务器
servers or five or seven or whatever
系统会随着我们的添加而变得更快吗
does the system get faster as we add
更多的CPU，更多的马力去做
more more CPUs more horsepower to it do
你觉得你的实验室会变得更快
you think your labs will get faster as
假设你有更多的复制品
you have more replicas assuming they're
每个副本都有自己的计算机，因此
each replicas its own computer right so
您确实可以获得更多的CPU周期
that you really do get more CPU cycles
随着您增加更多的收入
as you add more revenues
在所有的
between all the
是啊，是啊，这没什么大不了的
yeah yeah there's nothing about this
当您添加更多的内容时，这会使它变得更快
that makes it faster as you add more
服务生说的对，绝对是真的，就像
servers right it's absolutely true like
随着我们拥有更多的服务器，您知道
as we have more servers you know the
几乎可以肯定，领导者是一个瓶颈。
leader is almost certainly a bottleneck
因为领导必须处理每一个
cuz the leader has to process every
请求时，它会发送每个
request and it sends a copy of every
在您添加时向所有其他服务器发出请求
request to every other server as you add
更多的服务器，这只会增加更多的工作
more servers it just adds more work to
这个瓶颈节点，对，你不是
this bottleneck node right you're not
获得任何好处任何性能
getting any benefit any performance
从添加的服务器中获益，因为
benefit out of the added servers because
他们真的什么都没做
they're not really doing anything
他们只是都很开心地做任何事
they're just all happily doing whatever
领导告诉他们去做他们没有做的事
the leader tells them to do they're not
你知道从领先者身上减去
you know subtracting from the leaders
每一项工作和每一项操作都要
work and every single operation goes to
领导，所以在这里，你知道
the leader so for here you know the
你所知的表现是相反的
performance is you know inversely
与服务器数量成比例
proportional to the number of servers
如果您添加了更多服务器，则会在此添加更多服务器
that you add you add more servers this
几乎可以肯定会变得更低，因为
almost certainly gets lower because the
领导只是有更多的工作要做，所以在这件事上
leader just has more work so in this
系统我们有更多的问题
system we have the problem that more
服务器会使系统变慢，这就是
servers makes the system slower that's
太糟糕了，你知道这些服务器的价格是
too bad you know these servers cost a
每人几千美元，你就会
couple thousand bucks each and you would
希望你能用它们来
hope that you could use them to get
更好的性能是的
better performance yeah
好的，所以问题是如果
okay so the question is what if the
请求可能来自不同的客户端
requests may be from different clients
或连续的请求和相同的客户端
or successive requests and same client
或者别的什么，如果这些要求适用怎么办？
or something what if the requests apply
这个州的两个完全不同的地方
two totally different parts of the state
所以你知道在密钥值商店里也许
so you know in a key value store maybe
其中一个是穿在X身上的，另一个是穿在X身上的
one of them is a put on X and the other
是一个装腔作势的人，好像和这件事没什么关系
was a put on Y like nothing to do with
你认识的彼此我们能带上
each other you know can we take
这一点的优势和答案是
advantage of that and the answer that is
现在绝对不在这个框架内
absolutely now not in this framework
不过，或者它是我们能做到的中心
though or it's the center which we can
好好利用它吧，它是非常有限的。
take advantage of it it's very limited
在这个框架中，它可以很好地
in this framework it could be well at a
高层领导对一切的要求
high level the leader the requests all
还是要经过领队和
still go through the leader and the
领导还是要把它发给所有人
leader still has to send it out to all
复制品和那里的复制品越多
the replicas and the more replicas there
领导者要传达的信息就越多
are the more messages the leader has to
所以在高层发送，不太可能
send so at a high level it's not likely
去这种交换性的或社区的
to this sort of commutative or community
请求的数量不太可能对此有所帮助
of requests is not likely to help this
情况是一个值得保留的奇妙想法
situation is a fantastic thought to keep
别忘了，因为这绝对会
in mind though because it'll absolutely
在其他系统中出现，人们会
come up in other systems and people will
能够在其他地方利用它
be able to take advantage of it in other
系统正常，所以有一点
systems okay so so there's a little bit
服务器硬件方面令人失望的事实
disappointing facts with server hardware
对表演没有帮助，所以非常
wasn't helping performance so a very
很明显，也许是最简单的方式
sort of obvious maybe the simplest way
你也许可以利用这些
that you might be able to harness these
其他服务器正在构建一个系统，在该系统中
other servers is build a system in which
您的写入请求都必须通过
ya write requests all have to go through
领导者，但在现实世界中却是一个巨大的
the leader but in the real world a huge
读取繁重的工作负载的数量
number of workloads are read heavy that
是不是有更多的读物，比如当你
is there's many more reads like when you
看看网页，你知道这就是一切
look at web pages you know it's all
关于读取数据以生成Web
about reading data to produce the web
页面和一般都有非常多
page and generally there are very
相对较少的权利，这是真实的
relatively few rights and that's true of
有很多系统，所以也许我们会把
a lot of systems so maybe we'll send
对领导者的权利，但只是送去杂草
rights to the leader but send weeds just
其中一个复制品，只需挑选
to one of the replicas right just pick
其中一个复制品，如果您有一个
one of the replicas and if you have a
只读请求，如实验3中的GET
read-only request like a get in lab 3
只要把它寄给其中一个复制品
just send it to one of the replicas and
如果我们现在这样做，我们就不会对领导说
not to the leader now if we do that we
虽然对人权没有太大帮助
haven't helped rights much although
我们减少了大量的阅读工作
we've gotten a lot of read workload off
领导，所以这可能会有帮助，但是我们
the leader so maybe that helps but we
绝对取得了巨大的进步
absolutely have made tremendous progress
读取，因为现在服务器越多
with reads because now the more servers
我们添加的客户端越多，我们可以支持的客户端就越多
we add the more clients we can support
对，因为我们只是平分
right because we're just splitting the
客户领导工作
client lead work
跨不同的复制副本，因此
across the different replicas so the
问题是如果我们让客户
question is if we have clients send
直接送到复制品，我们是不是要
directly to the replicas are we going to
快快乐乐的
be happy
是的，所以最新的是正确的是
yeah so up-to-date does the right is the
在类似木筏的系统中使用正确的词
right word in a raft like system which
ZooKeeper是如果客户端发送请求
zookeeper is if a client sends a request
到一个随机的复制品，你知道的
to a random replica you know sure the
您知道的复本中有一份日志副本
replica you know has a copy the log in
如果你知道它一直在执行
it you know it's been executing along
和领队在一起，你知道的，在实验3
with the leader and you know for lab 3
它有这个键值表格，而你
it's got this key value table and you
我知道你做了一个键X的GET，它是
know you do a get for key X and it's
会有四张关键的出走桌子
gonna have some four key exodus table
它可以回复你这样一种
and it can reply to you so sort of
从功能上讲，复制品得到了所有
functionally the replicas got all the
它需要响应客户端的条目
pieces it needs to respond to client to
来自客户端的读取请求
read requests from clients the
困难在于没有理由
difficulty is that there's no reason to
相信任何人的复制品除了
believe that anyone replicas other than
领导是最新的，因为很好
the leader is up to date because well
有一大堆原因可以解释为什么
there's a bunch of reasons why why
以下副本之一可能不是最新的
replicas may not be up to date one of
就是他们可能不在
them is that they may not be in the
领袖等待的多数
majority that the leader was waiting for
你想一想木筏在做什么
you think about what raft is doing the
领导只有义务等待
leader is only obliged to wait for
对其附加条目的响应来自
responses to its append entries from a
大多数追随者，然后它
majority of the followers and then it
可以提交操作并继续
can commit the operation and go on to
下一个操作，所以如果这个复制品
the next operation so if this replica
它可能永远不会占多数
wasn't in the majority it may never have
看到一场骚乱，可能是网络
seen a riot it may be the network
它掉了，再也没有拿到，所以是的
dropped it and never got it and so yeah
你认识领导，你认识一个
you know the leader and you know a
大多数服务器都已看到
majority of the servers have seen the
前三个请求，但你知道这一点
first three requests but you know this
服务器只看到了它的前两个
server only saw the first two it's
错过了B，所以读起来就是对你的读
missing B so read to be a read of you
知道那里应该有什么，我就在那里
know what should be there I'll just be
从这辆车里得到的完全是陈旧的价值
totally get a stale value from this one
即使这个复制品真的看到了这个
even if this replica actually saw this
新日志条目它可能缺少
new log entry it might be missing the
提交命令你知道这个动物园管理员
commit command you know this zookeepers
应用程序与先将其放入筏子的方式相同
app as much the same as raft it first
发送日志条目，然后当
sends out a log entry and then when the
领导人获得了大多数积极的支持
leader gets a majority of positive
作为回答，领导发出了一个
replies the leader sends out a
通知说是的我要
notification saying yeah I'm gonna
提交我可能没有的日志条目
committing that log entry I may not have
得到了承诺和最糟糕的情况
gotten the commit and the sort of worst
案例版本，尽管它的
case version of this although its
相当于我已经说过的是
equivalent to what I already said is
对于所有客户端和所有客户端
that for all this client for all client
要知道此复制副本可能已分区
to knows this replica may be partitioned
从领导那里，或者仅仅是绝对的
from the leader or may just absolutely
与领导完全没有联系，
not be in contact with leader at all and
你知道追随者并不是真的
you know the follower doesn't really
有办法知道
have a way of knowing
实际上它刚刚被切断了一个
that actually it's just been cut off a
刚刚从领导那里发来的，只是不是
moment ago from the leader and just not
得到任何东西，这样你就不需要知道了
getting anything so you know without
如果我们想要更聪明的话
some further cleverness if we want to
建立一个我们不能线性化的系统
build a linearizable system we can't
玩这个游戏把有吸引力的
play this game of sending the attractive
就目前的表现而言，我们不能
it as it is for performance we can't
在复制件上玩这个游戏，发送一个
play this game at replicas sending a
对复制副本的读取请求，并且您
read request to the replicas and you
实验3也不应该这样做，因为
shouldn't do it for lab 3 either because
这3个也应该是
that 3 is also supposed to be
可以线性化，任何问题都可以
linearizable it's any any questions
关于为什么线性化能力禁止我们
about why linearize ability forbids us
让副本为客户端提供服务可以
from having replicas serve clients ok
你知道证据就是我把它弄丢了
you know that the proof is the I lost it
但是证据就是这么简单
now but the proof was that simple
阅读你知道的正确的一个正确的阅读
reading you know right one right to read
我早些时候在黑板上举了一个例子
one example I put on the board earlier
你不是很多，只是你知道这不是
you not a lot just you know this is not
中的陈旧数据提供服务。
allowed to serve stale data in the
线性可线性化系统可以，那么怎么做呢？
linear linearizable system ok so how
哦，那我们的交易是怎么做的呢？
does how does ooh keep our deal with
这位动物园管理员真的做得到吗？
this zookeeper actually does you can
从表2可以看出您在表中查找
tell from table two you look in Table
两名动物园管理员阅读性能上升
two zookeepers read performance goes up
随着您添加更多服务器，
dramatically as you add more servers so
显然动物园管理员在玩游戏
clearly zookeepers playing some game
这里允许的必须是允许它
here which allows must be allowing it to
返回只读以提供只读服务
return read only to serve read only
来自其他服务器的请求
requests from the additional servers the
那么Ooh Keeper是如何制作复制品的呢？
replicas so how does ooh keeper make
这个保险箱
this safe
是的，我的意思是，实际上它几乎是
that's right I mean in fact it's almost
不允许说它确实需要
not allowed to say it does need the
最近写的，是的，动物园管理员的方式
written latest yeah the way zookeeper
剥了这只猫的皮就是它不是
skins this cat is that it's not
可线性化的权利，他们只是喜欢
linearizable right they just like to
找出这个问题并说好
find away this problem and say well
我们不会的我们不会的
we're not gonna be we're not going to
提供可线性化读取等功能
provide linearizable reads and so
所以你没有义务
therefore you don't are not obliged
你知道动物园管理员没有义务
you know zookeepers not obliged to
提供允许读取的最新数据
provide fresh data to reads it's allowed
根据它的一致性规则，这些规则是
by its rules of consistency which are
不能线性化以产生陈旧数据
not linearizable to produce stale data
对惠顿来说，所以它在某种程度上已经解决了
for Wheaton's so it's sort of solved
这个技术问题是一种
this technical problem with a kind of
魔杖的定义波通过说
definitional wave of the wand by saying
嗯，我们从来不欠你可线性化的东西。
well we never owed you them linearizable
它会被放在第一位，所以它不是
it'll be in the first place so it's not
如果你不提供它，那就是一个错误，那就是
a bug if you don't provide it and that's
实际上，这是一种非常经典的方式
actually a pretty classic way to
以此来接近某种
approach this to approach the sort of
履约与严格之间的紧张关系
tension between performance and strict
而强烈的一致性就是不
and strong consistency is to just not
尽管如此，仍然提供了很强的一致性
provide strong consistency nevertheless
我们必须把我们的思想放在心底
we have to keep in the back of our minds
如果系统没有
question of if the system doesn't
提供线性化能力还是它
provide linearize ability is it still
会很有用，对吧，你做一个
going to be useful right and you do a
读一读，你就不会明白当前的潮流
read and you just don't get the current
答案或当前正确答案
answer or current correct answer the
最新的数据，比如我们为什么认为
most latest data like why do we believe
这将产生一个有用的
that that's gonna produce a useful
系统，所以让我来谈谈这一点
system and so let me talk about that so
首先，有没有任何关于
first of all any questions about about
动物园管理员真正要做的基本问题是
the basic problem zookeeper really does
允许客户端发送只读请求
allow client to send read-only requests
发送到任何复制副本，并且该复制副本响应
to any replica and the replica responds
从它目前的状态中解脱出来
out of its current state and that
复制可能滞后，其日志可能
replicate may be lagging it's log may
没有最新的日志条目，并且
not have the very latest log entries and
因此它可能会返回过时数据，即使
so it may return stale data even though
有一个更新的承诺价值
there's a more recent committed value
好的，那么我们还剩下什么呢？
okay so what are we left with
动物园管理员确实有一些它
zookeeper does actually have some it
确实有一套一致性
does have a set of consistency
保证这样做是为了帮助那些写作的人
guarantees so to help people who write
基于ZooKeeper的应用程序原因
zookeeper based applications reason
关于他们的应用程序是什么
about what their applications what's
实际上会发生在他们奔跑的时候
actually going to happen when they run
他们是这样的
them so
而这些担保都与
and these guarantees have to do with
排序为真正的线性化能力
ordering as indeed linearise ability
是这样吗？动物园管理员确实有两个主要的
does so zookeeper does have two main
保证他们声明这是
guarantees that they state and this is
第2.3节其中一条是不是说
section 2.3 one of them is it says that
权利或现在可以线性化的权利
rights rights or linearizable now you
我知道有可线性化的概念
know there are notion of linearizable
可能和我的不太一样
isn't not quite the same in mine maybe
因为他们在谈论权利不
because they're talking about rights no
珠子他们在这里的真正意思是
beads what they really mean here is that
系统的行为就好像即使
the system behaves as if even though
客户端可以并发提交权限
clients might submit rights concurrently
尽管如此，系统的行为就好像它
nevertheless the system behaves as if it
中一次执行一个权限。
executes the rights one at a time in
一些顺序，且确实服从实时
some order and indeed obeys real-time
权利的排序，因此如果一项权利具有
ordering of right so if one right has
被视为先于另一人完成
seen to have completed before another
权利已经下达，那么做保管人遗嘱
right has issued then do keeper will
实际上，它的行为就像它执行了第二个
indeed act as if it executed the second
就在第一个右转弯之后，所以它是
right after the first right so it's
权限但不是读取是可线性化的
rights but not reads are linearizable
动物园看守人并不是一个严格的读写人
and zookeeper isn't a strict readwrite
系统中实际上有一些权利
system there are actually rights that
也隐含着阅读，对于那些类型的
imply reads also and for those sort of
混合权利，那些你认识的人
mixed rights those those you know any
任何修改状态的操作都是
any operation that modifies the state is
相对于所有其他
linearizable with respect to all other
修改状态的操作
operations that modify the state the
给予的其他保证是任何
other guarantee of gives is that any
给定客户端，其操作在
given client its operations executes in
客户端指定的顺序
the order specified by the client
他们称之为先进先出客户订单
they call that FIFO client order
这意味着如果一个
and what this means is that if a
特定客户发布权限并
particular client issues a right and
然后是读，然后是读，然后是右
then a read and then a read and a right
或者不管是什么，最重要的权利
or whatever that first of all the rights
从适合客户端序列
from that sequence fit in in the client
按以下总体顺序指定顺序
specified order in the overall order of
所有客户的权利，所以如果客户说
all clients rights so if a client says
做好这件事，然后做好那件事，然后
do this right then that right and the
最后权利顺序中的第三权利
third right in the final order of rights
将看到客户端速率出现在
will see the clients rates occur in the
为此指定的客户的顺序
order of the client specified so for
这是我们的客户指定的权利
rights this is our client specified
订单，这是特别的，你知道的
order and this is particularly you know
这是系统的一个问题，因为
this is a issue with the system because
允许客户端启动
clients are allowed to launch
异步权限请求，该请求是
asynchronous right requests that is a
客户端可以发出一系列完整的
client can fire off a whole sequence of
领队对动物园管理员的权利
rights to the leader to the zookeeper
领队，不用等他们中的任何一个
leader without waiting for any of them
要完成并按顺序恢复
to complete and in order resume the
报纸上并没有明确写到这一点，但是
paper doesn't exactly say this but
想必是为了让领导人
presumably in order for the leader to
实际上能够执行客户端
actually be able to execute the clients
客户端指定顺序中的权限
rights in the client specified order
我们在想象我在想象
we're imagining I'm imagining that the
客户端实际标记其写入
client actually stamps its write
有数字的请求，并说你
requests with numbers and saying you
我知道我会先做这件事，这件事
know I'll do this one first this one
第二，这三分之一和动物园管理员
second this one third and the zookeeper
领导服从命令的权利，所以这是
leader obeys that ordering right so this
特别有趣，因为这些
is particularly interesting due to these
异步写入请求和用于
asynchronous write requests and for
读起来这有点复杂
reads this is a little more complicated
我之前说的理由不会消失
the reasons I said before don't go
通过所有写入都通过
through the writes all go through the
领队读书会刚刚去了一些
leader the reads just go to some
复制品，所以他们看到的只有
replicas and so all they see is the
那些碰巧被送到这里的东西
stuff that happens to have made it to
那些复制品以我们应该记录的方式记录
that replicas log the way we're supposed
要考虑FIFO客户订单，请执行以下操作
to think about the FIFO client order for
读取的情况是，如果客户端发出
reads is that if the client issues a
按某种顺序再次读取的顺序
sequence of reads again in some order
客户读到一件事，然后
the client reads one thing and then
另一件事，然后是第三件事
another thing and then a third thing
相对于复制副本上的日志
that relative to the log on the replicas
与这些客户交谈时，每个读者都有
talking to those clients reads each have
中的某个特定点发生
to occur at some particular point in the
日志，否则他们需要在某种程度上观察
log or they need to sort of observe the
状态，因为该状态存在于
state as it as the state existed at a
特定点
particular point
日志，此外，
the log and furthermore that the
连续读取必须观察点
successive reads have to observe points
不会倒退，也就是说，如果一个
that don't go backwards that is if a
客户端发出一次读取，然后发出另一次读取
client issues one read and then another
读取，第一次读取在此执行
read and the first read executes at this
在日志中第二次读取的指针是
point in the log the second read is that
你知道被允许以同样的方式执行它
you know allowed to execute it the same
或日志中稍后的点，但不是
or later points in the log but not
允许按问题查看以前的状态
allowed to see a previous state by issue
一次读取，然后另一次读取
one read and then another read the
第二次读取必须查看处于以下位置的状态
second read has to see a state that's at
至少与第一个州一样最新
least as up-to-date as the first state
这是一个重要的事实
and that's a significant fact in that
我们要在推理的时候驾驭
we're gonna harness when we're reasoning
关于如何写正确的动物园管理员
about how to write correct zookeeper
应用程序及其位置
applications and where this is
特别令人兴奋的是，如果
especially exciting is that if the
客户端正在与一个复制副本对话，以获取
client is talking to one replica for a
同时，它会向以下对象发出一些读取问题
while and it issues some reads issue to
读这里，然后我读那里，如果这是
read here and then I read there if this
复制副本失败，客户端需要
replica fails and the client needs to
开始将其读取发送到另一个
start sending its read to another
保证此FIFO客户端的副本
replica that guaranteed this FIFO client
或者担保仍然有效，如果客户
or a guarantee still holds if the client
切换到新的复制副本，因此
switches to a new replica and so that
意思是如果你在坠机前就知道
means that if you know before a crash
客户读了一遍那种锯子
the client did a read that sort of saw
在日志中的这一点上声明
state as of this point in the log that
意味着客户希望新的
means when the clients wishes to the new
复制副本，如果它向您发出另一次读取
replicas if it issues another read you
知道这是它之前执行的读取
know it's its previous read executed
这里
here
如果客户端发出另一次读取，
if a client issues another read that
Read必须在此时执行，否则
read has to execute at this point or
后来即使它交换了复制品
later even though it's switched replicas
你知道这件事的运作方式是
and you know the way this works is that
这些日志条目中的每一个都由
each of these log entries is tagged by
引导者使用Z X ID对其进行标记，该ID
the leader tags it with a Z X ID which
基本上只是一个条目编号
is basically just a entry number
每当复制副本响应客户端时
whenever a replica responds to a client
读请求，您知道它执行了
read request it you know executed the
在特定点请求，并且
request at a particular point and the
复制副本使用以下项的Z X ID进行响应
replica responds with the Z X ID of the
紧挨着之前的日志条目返回到
immediately preceding log entry back to
客户端记得的客户端是
the client the client remembers this was
您的最新数据的EXID
the exid of the most recent data you
知道是我见过的最高的zx点子
know is the highest z x idea i've ever
在客户端发送请求时看到
seen and when the client sends a request
复制到相同或不同的复制副本
to the same or a different replica it
随之而来的是他们的要求
accompanies their request with that
有史以来最高的CX ID
highest CX ID has ever seen and that
告诉另一个复制品啊哈你知道我
tells this other replica aha you know i
需要通过以下方式响应该请求
need to respond to that request with
至少与此相关的数据
data that's at least relative to this
在日志中指向
point in a log
这很有趣，如果你知道的话
and that's interesting if this you know
此复制副本不在第二个复制副本上
this replicas not up this second replica
更不是最新的，是的，那时候是的
is even less up to date yes was then
接收到其中的任何一个，但它接收到一个
received any of these but it receives a
客户的请求客户说哦
request from a client the client says oh
天哪，我上次读的时候执行了这个
gosh the last read I did executed this
日志和其他一些复制副本中的点
spot in the log and some other replica
此复制副本需要等待，直到它
this replica needs to wait until it's
将整个日志记录到这一点
gotten the entire log up to this point
在它被允许响应
before it's allowed to respond to the
客户，我不太清楚这是怎么回事
client and I'm not sure exactly how that
工作，但要么复制品只是
works but either the replicas just
延迟对读取的响应，或者可能
delays responding to the read or maybe
它拒绝阅读并说，你看，我只是
it rejects the read and says look I just
不知道谈话的信息
don't know the information talk to
其他人或者以后再跟我说
somebody else or talk to me later
你知道这个最终会在哪里
where's eventually the you know this
如果已连接，复本将会赶上
replica will catch up if it's connected
给领导，然后你就不能
to the leader and then you won't be able
回应
to respond
好的，所以阅读是有序的，他们只会
okay so reads are ordered they only go
在时间上前进或仅在时间内前进
forward in time or only go forward in
一种日志顺序，还有一件事
sort of log order and a further thing
我相信这是关于理性的真理
which I believe is true about reason
权限是读写FIFO
rights is that reads and writes the FIFO
客户订单适用于所有客户
client order applies to all of a clients
所有单个客户端都请求，因此如果我
all of a single clients requests so if I
从客户端进行写入，然后我发送一个
do a write from a client and I send a
给领导写信需要时间
write to the leader it takes time before
该写入已提交发送
that write is sent out committed
不管怎样，我可以把它直接寄给
whatever so I may send it right to the
领队领队没有处理它或
leader the leader hasn't processed it or
已经提交了，然后我发送了一个读取器
committed it yet and then I send a read
对于复制副本，读取可能必须停止
to a replica the read may have to stall
你知道为了保证先进先出
you know in order to guarantee FIFO
客户订购读数，他们必须
client order the read and they have to
拖延到此客户端实际
stall until this client has actually
查看并执行了以前的
seen and executed the previous the
客户端的上一次写入操作So
client's previous write operation so
那是这种类型的
that's a consequence of this type of
客户订单是权利被
client order is that a reason rights are
同样的顺序，你知道怎么走
in the same order and you know the way
要了解这一点，最明显的方法是如果一个
the most obvious way to see this is if a
客户端写入特定数据段
client writes a particular piece of data
你知道吗，给领导写封信
you know sends a write to the leader and
然后立即读取相同的
then immediately does a read of the same
并将读取数据发送到
piece of data and sends that read to a
复制品男孩，它最好看看它自己
replica boy it better see its own
如果我写了什么东西，写的值是对的
written value right if I write something
值为17，然后我做了一个读数
to have value 17 and then I do a read
它没有价值17，那就是
and it doesn't have value 17 then that's
太离奇了，这是天哪的证据
just bizarre and it's evidence that gosh
系统没有执行我的请求
the system was not executing my requests
因为那样它就会
in order because then it would have
执行写入，然后在
executed the write and then before the
读一读，所以一定有一些有趣的东西
read so there must be some funny
复制品业务停滞不前
business with the replicas stalling
客户端在发送读取和
the client must when it sends a read and
说，看，你知道我写的最后一封信
say look you know I the last write
请求我发送了一位具有ZX ID的领导
request I sent a leader with ZX ID
此复制品中的某些内容必须等待
something in this replica has to wait
直到它看到我是领导者是的
till it sees that I'm the leader yes
哦，当然了，所以我想你是什么
oh absolutely so I think what you're
据观察，从复制副本读取
observing is that a read from a replica
可能看不到最新数据，因此
may not see the latest data so the
领袖可能已经向多数派发出了C
leader may have sent out C to a majority
复制副本，并提交它和
of replicas and committed it and the
大多数人可能已经执行了，但是如果我们的
majority may have executed it but if our
我们说的复制品不在里面
replica that we're talking wasn't in
大多数人可能这个复制品没有
that majority maybe this replica doesn't
有最新的数据，那就是
have the latest data and that just is
动物园管理员的工作方式，它确实是这样做的
the way zoo keeper works and so it does
不能保证我们会看到最新的
not guarantee that we'd see the latest
所以如果有保证的话
data so if there there is a guarantee
关于ReadWrite排序，但它只是
about readwrite ordering but it's only
每个客户端，因此如果我发送写入并
per client so if I send a write in and
然后我把数据读入系统
then I read that data the system
保证我的珠子遵守我的
guarantees that my bead observes my
好的，如果你发一个右拳，然后我
right if you send a right in and then I
阅读你写的数据这不是
read the data that you wrote this isn't
不能保证我看到你的权利
does not guarantee that I see your right
你知道这就像是
and that's and you know that's like the
他们如何获得加速的基础
foundation of how they get speed up for
读数与
reads proportional to the number of
复制品
replicas
但我要说的是，这个系统不是
but I would say the system isn't
可线性化，但它不是那样的
linearizable and and but it is not that
它没有属性，则权利是
it has no properties then the rights are
当然有很多好的，所有的权利都来自
certainly many all right all rights from
所有客户一次形成一个客户
all clients form some one at a time
序列，所以这是一种意义上的
sequence so that's a sense in which the
权利所有的权利都是可笑的膝盖
rights all rights are the knee risible
和每个单独的客户端操作
and each individual clients operations
可能这意味着它也是可线性化的
may be this means linearizable also it
你知道吗，这可能意味着
may you know this this probably means
每个单独的客户操作
that each individual clients operations
线性化得很好，虽然我还不是很清楚
are linearize well though I'm not quite
当然你知道我其实不知道怎么做
sure you know I'm actually not sure how
它是有效的，但这是合理的
it works but that's a reasonable
那么假设当我发送一个
supposition then when I send in an
异步权限，系统不会
asynchronous right the system doesn't
尚未执行，但它确实回复了我
execute it yet but it does reply to me
说，是的，你知道我有你的权利
saying yeah you know I got your right
这是这个牦牛的身份证，它会
and here's this yaks ID that it will
如果它被承诺了，我只想开始
have if it's committed I just like start
返回所以这是一个合理的理论
return so that's a reasonable theory I
我不知道它是怎么做到的
don't actually know how it does it and
如果客户端不阅读，则它需要
then the client if it doesn't read needs
为了让复制品看起来像你知道的
to tell the replicas look you know
是的，我做了，你知道，如果我做一个
that's right I did you know if I do a
数据的读取是操作的一部分
read of the data is of the operation
好的，如果您将读取发送到复制副本
okay so if you send a read to a replica
作为回报，复制品会让你知道
the replicas in return you that you know
实际上，这是从这张表中读取的数据
really it's a read from this table is
什么你不可能名义上是什么
what your no way notionally what the
客户认为它在这么做，你的客户
client thinks it's doing so you client
这就是我想读这行的全部内容
says all I want to read this row from
此复本发送的服务器的此表
this table the server this replica sends
返回该表当前值
back its current value for that table
加上上次操作的GX ID
plus the GX ID of the last operation
更新了该表
that updated that table
是啊，所以实际上我是我不是
yeah so there's so actually I'm I'm not
准备好做两件事，那就是
prepared to so the the two things that
会很有意义，而且我认为这两种情况中的任何一种
would make sense and I think either of
他们会没事的，因为服务器可以
them would be okay is the server could
对于每个表行，都要跟踪这一点。
track this yet for every table row the
最后一个右操作的ZX ID
ZX ID of the last right operation that
触摸它，或者它可以让所有人都能读到
touched it or it could just to all read
请求将ZX ID作为最后一个返回
requests returned the ZX ID as a last
其日志中的已提交操作
committed operation in its log
不管那是不是最后一次
regardless of whether that was the last
触摸行操作，因为所有
operation of touch that row because all
我们要做的就是确保客户
we need to do is make sure that client
请求按顺序向前移动，因此我们
requests move forward in the order so we
只是需要一些东西来回报一些东西
just need something to return something
它大于或等于
that's greater than or equal to the
对上一次接触到的数据
right that last touched the data that
客户读得很好，所以这些是
the client read all right so these are
保证书所以你知道我们还是离开了
the guarantees so you know we still left
带着一个问题，那就是是否有可能
with a question of whether it's possible
要对此进行合理的编程，请执行以下操作
to do reasonable programming with this
一套保证，答案是好的
set of guarantees and the answer is well
这是你在高层次上知道的，这是
this you know at a high level this is
不如可线性化的好，它是一个
not quite as good as linearizable it's a
更难理解的是
little bit harder to reason about and
有更多的问题，比如阅读
there's sort of more gotchas like reads
可以返回过时的数据，但不会发生
can return stale data just can't happen
在一个可线性化的系统中，但是它
in a linearizable system but it's
尽管如此，好到足以使
nevertheless good enough to do to make
这是相当直截了当的道理
it pretty straightforward to reason
关于很多你可能想要做的事情
about a lot of things you might want to
和动物园管理员一起做，所以有一个，所以我
do with zookeeper so there's a so I'm
我可能会试着构思一个论点
gonna try to construct an argument maybe
通过举例说明为什么这不是一个糟糕的
by example of why this is not such a bad
顺便说一句，编程模型是一个原因
programming model one reason by the way
就是有一种外在的存在，这就是
is that there's an out there's this
名为接收器的操作，该接收器
operation called sink which is
本质上是写操作，如果
essentially a write operation and if a
客户，你知道的，假设我知道
client you know supposing I know that
你最近写了一些你是个
you recently wrote something you being a
不同的客户和我想看什么
different client and I want to read what
你写的所以我想要最新的数据
you wrote so I actually want fresh data
我可以送一个这样的水槽进去
I can send in one of these sink
有效地很好地
operations which is effectively well the
同步操作通过
sync operation makes its way through the
系统，就好像它是一次写入，而您
system as if it were a write and you
我知道最终会出现在我的日志里
know finally showing up in the logs of
这些复制品真的至少是
the replicas that really at least the
我正在与之交谈的复制品，然后我
replicas that I'm talking to and then I
可以回来读一读，你知道
can come back and do a read and you know
我能，我基本上能分辨出复制品
I can I can tell the replica basically
在你看完这份读物之前，不要提供这个读物
don't serve this read until you've seen
我的最后一个水槽，它真的掉了出来
my last sink and that actually falls out
当然是从第五个客户的订单开始，如果我们
naturally from fifl client order if we
如果我们向右倒下，那么5-0
if we countersink as a right then five-o
客户订单称需要读取以
client order says reads are required to
看你知道的州你知道至少有
see state you know there's as least as
最新的是从那以后的最后一条路。
up to date is the last right from that
客户端，所以如果我发送一个接收器，
client and so if I send in a sink and
然后我读到了我就是这个系统
then I do read I'm the the system is
有义务给我数据，那就是签证到期了
obliged to give me data that's visas up
到目前为止，我的水槽在原木中的位置
to date as where my sink fell in the log
如果我需要看书的话还是点吧
order anyway if I need to read
在接收器中发送最新数据，然后执行
up-to-date data send in a sink then do a
读取，并且读取保证会看到
read and the read is guaranteed to see
截至输入时的数据
data as of the time the same was entered
放到原木里，相当新鲜，所以
into the log so reasonably fresh so
那只是一只，但是很贵的。
that's one out but it's an expensive one
因为你现在我们把一个便宜的
because you now we converted a cheap
读入接收器操作，该接收器操作
read into the sink operation which
耗尽了领队的时间，所以这是一个
burned up time on the leader so it's a
不-不，如果你不需要的话，但这是
no-no if you don't have to do but here's
下面是几个场景示例，这些场景
a couple of examples of scenarios that
这篇论文谈到了这一推理
the paper talks about that the reasoning
关于它们的描述是简化的或合理的
about them is simplified or reasonably
很简单，考虑到这里的规则，所以
simple given the rules that are here so
首先，我想谈谈
first I want to talk about the trick in
第2.3节包含就绪文件，其中
section 2.3 of with the ready file where
我们假设有一些大师和
we assume there's some master and the
在中维护配置的大师级人员
Masters maintaining a configuration in
ZooKeeper是一堆文件和
zookeeper which is a bunch of files and
动物园管理员描述了你知道的
zookeeper that describe you know
关于我们的分布式系统
something about our distributed system
比如所有员工的IP地址
like the IP addresses of all the workers
也不知道主人是谁之类的，所以我们
or who the master is or something so we
更新这个的大师
the master who's updating this
配置，也许还有一堆
configuration and maybe a bunch of
需要阅读当前
readers that need to read the current
配置，并且需要每隔一段时间查看一次
configuration and need to see it every
时间会改变，所以问题是
time it changes and so the question is
你知道我们能不能建造一些
you know can we construct something that
即使在更新配置时
even though updating the configure even
尽管配置被拆分到
though the configuration is split across
在ZooKeeper中有很多文件，我们可以
many files in zookeeper we can have the
原子更新的效果，以便
effect of an atomic update so that
工人们看不到工人们在看着
workers don't see workers that look at
该配置没有看到一种
the configuration don't see a sort of
部分更新的配置，但仅限
partially updated configuration but only
一部完全更新的，那是一部经典之作
a completely updated that's a classic
这种配置
kind of thing that this configuration
动物园饲养员使用的管理
management that zookeeper people using
动物园管理员，所以你知道，看着
zookeeper for so you know looking at the
所以我们在复制2.3节
so we're copying what section 2.3
描述这会说主人是
describes this will say the master is
做了一系列的仪式来更新
doing a bunch of rites to update the
配置，下面是该配置的顺序
configuration and here's the order that
我们分布式系统的主站
the master for our distributed system
这些仪式是不是
does the rites
首先我们假设有一些准备好的
first we're assuming there's some ready
将名为Ready的文件归档，如果它们
file a file named ready and if they're
就绪文件存在，然后是配置
ready file exists then the configuration
我们被允许阅读
is we're allowed to read the
配置(如果它们已准备好文件)
configuration if they're ready files
缺少，这意味着配置是
missing that means the configuration is
不断更新，我们不应该去看
being updated and we shouldn't look at
所以如果主机要更新
it so if the master is gonna update the
配置文件首先要做的是
configuration file the very first thing
它所做的就是删除准备好的文件，然后
it does is delete the ready file then it
写的各种文件都很动物园管理员
writes the various files very zookeeper
对象的数据所在的文件
files that hold the data for the
配置可能需要很多文件
configuration might be a lot of files
鼻子，然后当它完全
nose and then when it's completely
更新了组成
updated all the files that make up the
配置，然后重新创建
configuration then it creates again
那是准备好的文件
that's ready file
好的，到目前为止，语义是
alright so so far the semantics are
非常直截了当，这只是
extremely straightforward this is just
权利这里只有权利没有读
rights there's only rights here no reads
保证在
rights are guaranteed to execute in
线性顺序，我想现在我们必须
linear order and I guess now we have to
如果对第五个客户订单提出上诉
appeal the fifl client order if the
大师会给这些贴上这样的标签，哦，你知道的
master sort of tags these as oh you know
我希望我的权利按照这个顺序发生
I want my rights to occur in this order
那么读者就有义务进入它们。
then the reader is obliged to enter them
按该顺序添加到复制的日志中
into the replicated log in that order
所以尽管你知道复制品是
and so though you know the replicas were
所有人都尽职尽责地
all dutifully execute these one at a
这时候他们都会删除准备好的文件
time they'll all delete the ready file
然后把这个权利用在那个权利上
then apply this right in that right and
然后再次创建就绪文件，以便
then create the ready file again so
这些是命令的权利
these are rights the orders
不过，对于阅读来说，还是很直截了当的
straightforward for the reads though
它是，它可能有一点，也许是
it's it's maybe a little bit maybe a
根据需要稍微多想几句
little more thinking as required
假设我们有一些工人需要
supposing we have some worker that needs
要读取当前配置，我们正在
to read the current configuration we're
假设这名工人首先
going to assume that this worker first
检查以查看就绪文件是否
checks to see whether the ready file
存在它不存在它会给你
exists it doesn't exist it's gonna you
了解睡眠，然后再试一次，让我们假设
know sleep and try again so let's assume
它确实存在，让我们假设我们假设
it does exist let's assume we assume
工作人员检查以查看
that the worker checks to see
如果就绪文件在
if the ready file exists after it's
再创造出来，所以你知道这是什么
recreated and so you know what this
意思是现在这些都是正确的要求
means now these are all right requests
发送给领导，这是一次阅读
sent to the leader this is a read
请求，这只是一个集中的请求
request that's just centrally whatever
复制与之对话的客户端，然后
replica the clients talking to and then
如果它存在，你知道它会显示为F1
if it exists you know it's gonna read f1
B那-有趣的是
and B that - the interesting thing that
FIFO客户订单保证如下
FIFO client order guarantees here is
如果这返回了真，那就是如果
that if this returned true that is if
客户端正在与之对话的复制副本
the replica the client was talking to
说是的那份文件是存在的那么你就知道
said yes that file exists then you know
尽管如此，这意味着
as were as that what that means is that
至少在这个设置中是这样的
at least with this setup is that as that
该副本实际拥有副本
replica that that replica had actually
已查看就绪文件的重新创建
seen the recreate of the ready file
对的，为了让这个存在看到
right in order for this exist to see to
查看就绪文件是否存在，因为
see the ready file exists and because
需要连续的读取操作
successive read operations are required
在漫长的道路上只向前行进
to march along only forwards in the long
而且永远不会倒退，这意味着你
and never backwards that means that you
知道客户端的副本是否
know if the replicas the client was
如果它真的是原木的话
talking to if it's log actually
包含，然后它执行此操作
contained and then it executes this
创建就绪文件，这意味着
creative the ready file that means that
后续客户端读取必须仅移动
subsequent client reads must move only
按您的权限顺序转发
forward in the sequence of rights you
我知道领队把它放进了日志里
know that the leader put into the log so
如果我们看到这个已经准备好了，那就意味着
if we saw this ready that means that the
读取发生在复制副本借口
read occurs that the replica excuse to
在这里右手边的某个地方阅读
read down here somewhere after the right
它创造了就绪，这意味着
that created the ready and that means
保证读数能够遵守
that the reads are guaranteed to observe
这些权利的影响，所以我们这样做
the effects of these rights so we do
实际上在这里得到了一些好处
actually get some benefit here some
推理得益于这样一个事实，即
reasoning benefit from the fact that
即使它不能完全线性化
even though it's not fully linearizable
这些权利是可线性化的，并且
the rights are linearizable and the
阅读必须以一种单调的方式阅读
reads have to read sort of monotonically
在时间上向前移动到日志是
move forward in time to the log yes
主题音乐
[Music]
是的，这是个很好的问题，所以你的
yeah so that's a great question so your
这个问题在所有的客户中都是很好的
question is well in all this client
知道你知道这是不是真的
knows you know if this is the real
创建者输入的场景
scenario that the creators entered in
日志，然后读取器到达
the log and then the read arrives at the
在该复制副本执行此操作之后的复制副本
replica after that replica executed this
令人毛骨悚然的准备好了，然后一切都好了
creepy ready then everything's
直截了当，但还有其他
straightforward but there's other
这些东西是什么样子的可能性
possibilities for how this stuff was
交错
interleaved
所以让我们来看一个更麻烦的
so let's look at a much more troubling
场景所以你提出的场景
scenario so the scenario you brought up
我恰好准备好谈论这件事
which I happen to be prepared to talk
关于那个，是的，你知道的
about is that yeah you know the the
在某个点上执行到
master at some point executed to a
删除READY，否则您会知道很久以前
delete of ready or you know way back in
给以前的某个大师这个大师计时
time some previous master this master
已创建就绪文件
created the ready file
您知道，在它完成更新
you know after it finished updating the
我要说的是，准备好了，因为我已经存在了
state I say ready for I existed for a
然后一些新的主人或者这个
while then some new master or this
师父需要更改
master needs to change the
配置释放就绪文件
configurations release the ready file
你知道这是不对的，对吧
you know it doesn't right right and
真正令人不安的是
what's really troubling is that the
需要读取此内容的客户端
client that needs to read this
配置可能已调用EXISTS
configuration might have called exists
要查看就绪文件是否存在于
to see whether the ready file exists at
这一次，好吧，你知道这一点
this time all right and you know at this
时间点是的，确定准备好的文件
point in time yeah sure the ready file
存在，然后时间流逝，客户端
exists then time passes and the client
为可能是
issues the reads for the maybe the
客户端读取生成以下内容的第一个文件
client reads the first file that makes
升级配置，但也许是因为你
up the configuration but maybe it you
然后它读取第二个文件
know and then it reads the second file
也许这个读取的文件完全来自于
maybe this file this read comes totally
在主服务器一直在更改
after the master has been changing the
配置，现在这位读者拥有
configurations so now this reader has
读一读这辆旧的F1损坏的混合动力车
read this damaged mix of f1 from the old
配置和新版本中的f2
configuration and f2 from the new
配置，没有理由
configuration there's no reason to
相信这将包含
believe that that's going to contain
除了损坏的信息以外的任何内容
anything other than broken information
所以第一个场景很棒
so so this first scenario was great the
场景是一场灾难，所以现在我们
scenario is a disaster and so now we're
开始进入到
starting to get into
类似于严重的挑战，这是一个
of like serious challenges which a
精心设计的API用于协调
carefully designed API for coordination
在分布式系统中的计算机之间
between machines in a distributed system
可能会帮助我们正确解决
might actually help us solve right
因为就像3号实验室一样，你知道你是
because like for lab 3 you know you're
我要建立一个PUT GET系统和一个
gonna build a put get system and a
简单的Lab 3式PUT猜题系统
simple lab 3 style put guessed system
你知道它会遇到这个问题
you know it would run into this problem
也就是没有任何工具来
too and just does not have any tools to
去处理它吧
deal with it
但是动物园管理员API实际上不仅仅是
but the zookeeper API actually is more
比这更聪明，它能应付得来
clever than this and it can cope with it
那么实际发生的事情是什么呢？
and so what actually happens the way you
实际上会使用Ooh Keeper的是
would actually use ooh keeper is that
当发送此消息的客户端存在时
when the client sent in this exists
请求询问此文件是否存在，并且
request to ask does this file exist and
会说这个文件不仅存在
would say not only does this file exist
但它会说你知道告诉我
but it would say you know tell me if it
EXISTS甚至在那个文件上设置了监视
exists even set a watch on that file
这意味着如果这些文件曾经被删除或
which means if the files ever deleted or
如果它不存在，如果它曾经被创建过
if it doesn't exist if it's ever created
但在这种情况下，如果它曾经是
but in this case if it if it is ever
删除了，请给我发个通知
deleted please send me a notification
此外，通知还包括
and furthermore the notifications that
动物园管理员让你知道这是
zookeeper sends you know it's a the
读者在这里，它只是在和一些
reader here it's only talking to some
复制副本这是所有复制副本正在执行的操作
replicas this is all the replicas doing
这些东西对它来说就是复制品
these things for it the replica
保证向您发送通知
guarantees to send a notification for
对此准备好的文件进行一些更改，请参阅
some change to this ready file at the
相对于回答的正确点
correct point relative to the responses
给客户的读数，那么这又是什么呢？
to the clients reads and so what that
意思是你知道，因为
means so you know because that the the
这意味着在这件事上
implication of that is that in this
您知道这些内容的场景
scenario in which you know these these
权利有点像是实时地放在这里
rights sort of fit in here in real time
可保证的是，如果您要求
the guarantee is that if you ask for a
看着一些东西，然后你就可以发布了
watch on something and then you issue
有些人读到如果你的复制品
some reads if that replica you're
谈话是为了执行一些应该做的事情
talking to execute something that should
在你的工作时间内触发手表
trigger the watch in during your
读取顺序，然后是复制副本
sequence of reads then the replica
保证将通知送达
guarantees to deliver the notification
关于手表的信息，然后它才会响应
about the watch before it responds to
任何你知道的读物都会看到
any read that came that you know saw the
在该点之后记录
log after the point
该操作所在的操作的
of the OP where the operation that
已触发手表通知
triggered the watch notification
执行，所以这是
executed and so this is the log on the
复制品，所以你知道如果是这样的话
replica and so you know if the so that
你知道FIFO客户的订单将会
you know the FIFO client ordering will
假设您知道每个客户端请求必须
say you know each client requests must
显然可以放在原木的某个地方
fit somewhere into the log apparently
这些都在日志里符合我们正在做的事
these fit in here in the log what we're
担心的是这种读取会发生
worried about is that this read occurs
在日志里，但是我们设置了这个表
here in the log but we set up this watch
而保证就是它将会收到
and the guarantee is that will receive
如果有人删除了此内容，请注意
the note if if somebody deletes this
文件，然后我们可以通知您
file and we can notified then that
通知将出现在
notification will will appear at the
客户端在读取之前生成
client before a read that yields
日志中随后的任何内容都将
anything subsequently in the log will
在我们收到
get the notification before we get the
任何阅读的结果，也就是看到
results of any read that's that saw
手术后日志里有什么东西
something in log after the operation
产生了通知，那又怎么样？
that produced the notification so what
这意味着删除就绪状态为
this means that the delete ready is
既然我们已经准备好了一块手表
gonna since we have a watch on the ready
精英们准备好了要提交的文件
file that elite ready is going to
生成通知，并且
generate a notification and that
保证通知是
notification is guaranteed to be
在f2的读取结果之前传递
delivered before the read result of f2
如果f2看对了这一秒
if f2 was gonna see this second right
这意味着在阅读之前
and that means that before the reading
客户端已在以下位置完成序列
client has finished the sequence in
它会查看它的配置
which it looks at the configuration it's
保证看到手表通知
guaranteed to see the watch notification
在它看到任何写入结果之前
before it sees the results of any write
那是在这个删除那个之后发生的
that happened after this delete that
已触发通知
triggered the notification
是谁生产的手表，也是由谁生产的
who generates the watch as well the
复制副本假设客户端正在通话
replica let's say the client is talking
发送到此复制副本，并且它将
to this replica and it sends in the
EXISTS请求EXIST文件室已读取
exists request the exist room has a read
仅与他的复制品一起发送的请求
only request it sends with his replica
复制品正被画在
the replica is being painting on the
在一桌手表旁说“哦，你”
side a table of watches saying oh you
知道某某客户要求提供
know such-and-such a client asked for a
请关注此文件，并进一步查看
watch on this file and furthermore the
值班是在特定的Z位置建立的
watch was established at a particular Z
客户端读取的X ID
X ID that is did a read that client did
对执行的复制副本执行的读取
a read with the replica executed the
此时在日志中读取并返回
read at this point in the log and return
结果是相对于
results are relative to this point in
会员欠手表的日志是
the log members owe that watch is
相对于日志中该点，且
relative to that point in the log and
然后，如果出现删除操作，您知道
then if a delete comes in you know for
每一个有q的操作都是如此
every operation that there s Q so it
看着这张小桌子，上面写着啊哈
looks in this little table it says aha
你知道吗，那上面有块表
you know the a there was a watch on that
文件，并且可能通过散列
file and maybe it's indexed by hash of
文件名或其他什么
filename or something
好的，那么问题是，哦，是的，这个
okay so the question is oh yeah this
此副本必须具有监视表
this replica has to have a watch table
你知道如果副本崩溃，
you know if the replica crashes and the
客户端是正式不同的副本
client is officially different replica
你知道表台怎么样吗？
you know what about the watch table
好的，这些已经确定了。
right it's already established these
看吧，答案是不会的。
watch and the answer to that is that no
您的复制副本的代表会使新的
the rep your replica crashes the new
您切换到的复本不会有
replica you switch to won't have the
观察表，但是客户端会得到一个
watch table and but the client gets a
在以下位置的适当时刻发出通知
notification at the appropriate point in
在一连串的响应中，它会返回
in the stream of responses it gets back
说不出你的复制品你是
saying oops your replica you were
和你谈话的时候坠毁了，所以客户
talking to you crashed and so the client
然后知道它必须完全重置
then knows it has to completely reset up
所有的东西都藏在里面
everything and so tucked away in in the
例如，缺少以下事件处理程序
examples are missing event handlers to
说，哦，天哪，你知道我们需要回去
say oh gosh you know we need to go back
如果我们得到一个
and we establish everything if we get a
通知我们的副本崩溃了
notification that our replicas crashed
好的，我会继续的。
all right I'll continuous